Albany Friends Meeting; Records apap166
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Albany Friends Meeting Records
1969-1991
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Albany Friends Meeting (1942-: Albany, N.Y.)
apap166
1.0 cubic ft.
This collection includes material related to the Albany Friends Meeting's social justice activities, specifically having to do with injustices within the New York State judicial system.
Collection X
Access
Access to this collection is unrestricted.
Acquisition Information
David Easter donated this collection to the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives in 2003 October.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is arranged alphabetically. There are no series.
Biographical History
Albany Friends Meeting is part of The Religious Society of Friends (Quakers). In addition to monthly meetings, this group also holds and sponsors a monthly peace vigil in front of the New York State Capitol. In the 1970s, the group would often rally and observe Court hearings while conducting activism work and sponsoring programs having to do with the injustice within the judicial system. In 1980, this group founded the Quaker Peace Tax Fund for "those moved to refuse payment of taxes which would otherwise be used for war preparation and military purposes."
Scope and Contents
The Albany Friends Meeting Records consists of material related to the Albany Friends Meeting's social justice activities. This material includes flyers and pamphlets as well as documents detailing the results of court watching, the student volunteers for their Pretrial Release Program, and Quaker Peace Tax Fund correspondence and meeting minutes. The collection also contains reports, manuals, newsletters, and outlines of court proceeding procedure.
Albany, New York; Social Activists and Public Advocates; Albany Friends Meeting (1942-: Albany, N.Y.); Society of Friends. New York (State).
- Albany County Coalition of Court Observers, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- The Albany County Coalition of Court Observers Minutes and Agendas, 1985; Undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Albany County Coalition of Courtwatchers, 1972; 1977; 1986; Undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Albany County Coalition of Courtwatchers, 1981 June 28; 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Albany County Legislature Regarding the Office of the Public Defender Proposal, Undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Albany Courtwatch Report on the Albany Police Court, 1982 February 8 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Albany Courtwatchers Report for May, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Albany Friends Correspondence, 1977-1986 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Albany Friends Pretrial- Bankers Trust Company Albany, 1984 October 01 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Albany Friends Pretrial Release Program, 1974 September 16; 1975 December 01 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Albany Friends Pretrial Release Program, 1975; 1983-1985; Undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Albany Friends Pretrial Release Program- Blank Form, Undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Albany Police Court- Albany County Courtwatch Project Guide, Undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Albany PD, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Albany Police Department Prisoner Running Sheets, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- American Friends Service Committee Middle Atlantic Region- Progress Report, 1969 July-1971 April (Box 1, Folder 16)
- "Criminal Justice- A Shared Responsibility" -National Interreligious Task Force on Criminal Justice, 1978 April 03 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Family Court, 1978; Undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Friendly Agitator, Friends Suburban Project, 1977 January (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Justice in New York- A Citizen's Guide to the Courts, Undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Manual for Welfare Advocates in NYC 3rd Edition- Community Action for Legal Services, Inc., 1976 September (Box 1, Folder 21)
- NYS Act to Amend the General Municipal Law, in Relation to the Fee for Deposit of Cash Bail and Partially Secured Bail Bond, 1977 January 05 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- NYS Coalition for Criminal Justice- Update, 1981 February 26; 1981 April 23 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- NYS Commission on Judicial Conduct- Annual Report, 1983 March (Box 1, Folder 24)
- People's Law School, Undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Pretrial Justice Quarterly, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Pretrial Procedures in the Criminal Courts, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- The Pretrial Reporter, Vol. III, No. 2, 1979 May (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Quaker House- Community Releases Organization, Phase II, 1974 January 18 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Quaker Information Center on Criminal Justice- The Struggle for Justice, 1977 September (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Quaker Peace and Tax Fund, 1976; 1979; 1983-1984 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Quaker Peace and Tax Fund, 1984-1989 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Quaker Peace and Tax Fund- Albany Meeting, 1980-1984 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Quaker Peace and Tax Fund Correspondence, 1985; 1991 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Quaker Peace and Tax Fund Meetings, 1985-1988 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Quaker Peace and Tax Fund Responses to Quest, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Quaker Project on Community Conflict, Undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Quaker War Tax Resistance, 1983; 1989; 1991 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- "Role and Process in the Criminal Court" by Donald J. Newman, Undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Tri-City Alternatives to Violence Program, Undated (Box 3, Folder 3)